<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
   xmlns:bf="http://id.loc.gov/ontologies/bibframe/"
   xmlns:bflc="http://id.loc.gov/ontologies/bflc/"
   xmlns:owl="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#"
   xmlns:rdaw="http://rdaregistry.info/Elements/w/"
   xmlns:rdax="https://doi.org/10.6069/uwlib.55.d.4#"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
   xmlns:sin="http://sinopia.io/vocabulary/"
>
  <rdf:Description rdf:nodeID="N6b4c1016ac604cf6a9a5dcec45251879">
    <bf:source rdf:resource="https://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/organizations/wau"/>
    <bflc:encodingLevel rdf:resource="https://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/menclvl/f"/>
    <bf:descriptionConventions rdf:resource="https://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/descriptionConventions/rda"/>
    <bf:status rdf:nodeID="N016c93900d814c5d9b5994ee62aecfe5"/>
    <bf:creationDate>2019-11-26</bf:creationDate>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://id.loc.gov/ontologies/bibframe/AdminMetadata"/>
    <bflc:catalogerID xml:lang="eng">cec23</bflc:catalogerID>
    <bf:descriptionLanguage rdf:resource="https://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/languages/eng"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="https://api.sinopia.io/resource/f015312e-8959-4f63-abc9-6f207aede0f1">
    <rdaw:P10256 rdf:resource="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85050567"/>
    <rdaw:P10223 xml:lang="eng">Biodiversity and conservation of woody plants</rdaw:P10223>
    <rdaw:P10331 xml:lang="eng">Biodiversity and conservation of woody plants</rdaw:P10331>
    <rdaw:P10330 xml:lang="eng">Contents: Part 1. Genetic diversity and conservation: Coconut genetic diversity, conservation and utilization / V. Arunachalam and M.K. Rajesh -- Genetic diversity and conservation of Mexican forest trees / Christian Wehenkel, Samantha del Rochio Mariscal-Lucero, Juan Pablo Jaramillo-Correa, Carlos Antonio López-Sánchez, J. Jesús Vargas-Hernández and Cuauhtémoc Sáenz-Romero -- Climate change, genetic diversity, and conservation of paleoendemic redwoods / M.R. Ahuja -- Mulberry (Morus spp.) genetic diversity, conservation and management / Amalendu Tikader and Kunjupillai Vijayan -- Conservation of forest genetic resources in Norway in a climate change perspective / Tore Skrøppa and Kjersti Bakkebø Fjellstad -- Use of molecular markers in the conservation management of tropical trees / S. Changtragoon, R. Jalonen and A.J. Lowe -- Genetic diversity utilization and conservation of neem (Azadirachta indica A. Juss.) / A.V.C. Silva, A.S. Jesus. A.N.R. Soares and A.S. Ledo -- Part 2. Biodiversity and conservation: Biotechnological approaches for conservation of the genus Pistacia / Hülya Akdemir and Ahmet Onay -- Biodiversity and conservation of Elaeis species / Maizura Ithnin, Norhalida Mohamed Serdari, Norziha Abdullah, Ahmad Kushairi and Rajinder Singh -- Conservation of woody plant diversity in Kenya / Kimberly E. Medley, John K. Maingi and Christine M. Mutiti -- Woody plant diversity and density in selected eucalyptus and other plantation forest species in Ethiopia / Shiferaw Alem and Muhammad Nakhooda -- Biodiversity and conservation of date palm / Abdel A. Abul-Soad, S. Mohan Jain and Mushtaque A. Jatoi -- Approaches for in vitro conservation of woody plants germplasm / Maria-Teresa González-Arnao, Natalia Dolce, Maria Elena González-Benito, Carlos R. Castillo Martínez and Carlos A. Cruz-Cruz -- Conservation of hardwood forest species / E. Corredoira, M.T. Martínez, M.C. Sanjosé and A. Ballester -- Diversity of trees in the Mesoamerican agroforestry system / Noel A. González-Valdicia, William Cetzal-Ix, Saikat Kumar Basu, Fernando Casanova-Lugo and Jesús F. Martinez-Puc -- Native trees and shrubs for ecosystem services and the redesign of resilient livestock production systems in the Mexican neotropics / Francisco Solorio, Luis Ramirez, Liz Trenchard, Lucero Sarabia, Julia Wright, Carlos Aguilar, Baldomero Solorio, Armin Ayala and Juan Ku.</rdaw:P10330>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="https://api.sinopia.io/resource/2862b1c2-934b-408e-abf8-64ca368994fd"/>
    <bf:adminMetadata rdf:nodeID="N6b4c1016ac604cf6a9a5dcec45251879"/>
    <rdaw:P10256>Woody plants--Conservation</rdaw:P10256>
    <sin:hasResourceTemplate>WAU:RT:RDA:Work:monograph</sin:hasResourceTemplate>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://rdaregistry.info/Elements/c/C10001"/>
    <rdaw:P10219 xml:lang="eng">2017</rdaw:P10219>
    <rdax:hasLcClassificationPartA>SD411</rdax:hasLcClassificationPartA>
    <rdax:hasLcClassificationPartB>.B56 2017</rdax:hasLcClassificationPartB>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:nodeID="N016c93900d814c5d9b5994ee62aecfe5">
    <bf:code xml:lang="eng">n</bf:code>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://id.loc.gov/ontologies/bibframe/Status"/>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
